

#### EXPERTISE

Microsoft All Programs
Planning&Organising
SAP
Eye for Trends
Forecasting and Planning
Event Planning
Detail Oriented
Market Trend Analysis

#### EDUCATION

2015 - 2019
BACHELOR OF ARTS
Fashion Buying Retail
Management
University For The Creative
Arts, Kent UK
2015
DIPLOMA

Business Law & Social Science Kaplan International College, London, UK

2013
HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA
Praktiska Gymnasium
Stockholm, Sweden

# Marina Asaad

### BUYING & PRODUCT SPECIALIST

CONTACTS

+46 70 471 62 01

Marina.Asaad@live.se

#### ABOUT ME

Experienced in the business and retail sector as well as buying and retail alongside a buying retail management degree, experienced at market research, product selection, contracting and supplier negotiations. Proven track record in identifying trends and optimizing inventory for optimal customer experiences and reaching targets.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan 2024- Present

Wholesale Account Coordinator - Weekday (H&M Group), Stockholm.

- Efficiently process wholesale orders from clients, ensuring accuracy and timeliness in order fulfillment.
- Collaborate with the sales team to identify potential wholesale opportunities, generate leads, and support sales initiatives.
- Track and monitor the progress of wholesale orders from placement to delivery, ensuring on-time delivery
- Work closely with other departments to ensure seamless operations and alignment with organisational goals.

Feb 2022 - Nov 2023

Procurement Agent - U.S Embassy in Stockholm, Department of State

- Monitored all purchase acquisitions and managed supplier and vendor relationships.
- Navigated and applied FAR/DFARS regulations and internal procedures for compliance.

#### LANGUAGES

English -Advanced Swedish - Native Arabic - Native Syriac - Native

#### CERTIFICATIONS

2020 - Jewellery Basics **AZZA FAHMY** 

2015 - Leadership Training **Studieförbundet Bilda** 

2013 - Makeup Artist Diploma **Praktiska Gymnasium** 

- Managed in house day to day procurement and larger projects.
- Proven expertise in managing various types of contracts and procurement processes while ensuring compliance with regulations.
- Handled Request for Quotation (RFQ) procedures, issuing RFQs to qualified vendors and evaluating their proposals to secure the best value for the government.

## Dec 2019 - Dec 2021

#### Buying Assistant - Media Markt HQ Stockholm

- Demonstrated ability to coordinate with suppliers, negotiate contracts, and ensure timely deliveries.
- Evaluated consumer preferences and behaviors, combined with market trends and historical data, to adjust and enhance campaigns.
- Proficient in SAP for generating financial reports, trend reports and product data sheets.
- Developing creative presentations for all stores.
- Proactive approach in identifying emerging market trends to curate competitive and attractive product assortments for all Sweden stores.

#### Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

#### Special Project Administrator - Swedbank HQ Stockholm

- Overseeing and managing Know Your Customer (KYC) projects.
- Conducted thorough customer due diligence, verifying and validating client information and documentation.
- Maintained a comprehensive understanding of anti-money laundering (AML) and counter-terrorism financing (CTF) regulations.

#### April - Aug 2018

# Beauty Merchandise Admin Assistant, Marks & Spencer, London, UK

- Assisted in product ordering, inventory management, and ensuring timely replenishment of beauty products.
- Contributed to the development of effective beauty merchandising strategies to drive sales and profitability.